Hi Guys I'll come back.
So let's talk about one of the most important activity in the entire project management and that is
Dervla project charter.
So in this video we are going to look at this activity and what our things are needed to be performed
here to develop a project chart.
Remember this is that activity which we are dealing and now as we head the discourse we will go to all
the knowledge areas where we have to review these activities.
It will have certain inputs outputs techniques which are used to perform those activities and these
are very important to understand the field of project management or for your PMP Exam.
So please be careful attention if you need.
You can stop the redeposit take notes.
I have seen that taking notes really help.
So I'm coming back to this activity.
This is basically about how we devlopment who develop it and why it is needed.
So project started is basically created at a predefined stage of a project.
So basically it happens at the start of a project without a project charter a project manager can not
initiate a project.
What I mean by that is that they need to create their project management plan.
They need to assign the sources who will work on it.
So unless until there's a project charter a project cannot exist.
This document formalizes the existence of a project that's five this is the first up moment which should
be created as soon as a project needs to be initiated and project cierto statement provide a kind of
approval to the project manager to start the process.
So these are the inputs tools and techniques and outputs of this activity.
We have a business document and business document could be in the form of business case benefit management
plan.
Then there are agreements and enterprise environmental factors like policies and all those things which
we have discussed earlier an organizational process a assets of these could be Templar's this could
be you know a similar documents used for other projects.
So all of that side of business case is vital unless until there's a business case in the form of business
is document or benefit management plan you cannot initiate a project started.
So you need to have these things to create a project charter and then usually the techniques which are
deployed are used to create project check if you're using some tools maybe you have to fill in the blanks
or enter data and few sections which can eventually produce a project chart to certain.
But largely it's a document.
Let me show you a project charter document.
And we covered that in a little video where I will walk you through with the entire process and you
will have to create that document as assignment for this course.
But just to give you some idea of what we're talking about here this is the project charter document.
You can also just mention project charter our project charters statements.
Basically it's a document which you'll have all these details will have a section which will provide
justification for the course then it will have additional sections like you know project objective success
criteria risk a high level of common assumptions.
What kind of risk and opportunities out there and a high level time line.
And of course the budget.
So this is a sample project Sharpless statement which you will create and I will also provide to this
template so if you want to simply admit it and use it in your company for your professional work that's
up to you.
So going back to our slide to these other techniques so we have expert judgment which basically means
when you use your expediency your past learning to do something.
We have data gathering like brainstorming focus group interviews so you use these three techniques to
get data from stakeholders and entered that information relevant information in your projects.
Document.
You have interpersonal and team skills conflict management facilitation meeting management and meetings
so as you as you can see it's all about you know in dealing with your stakeholders.
So these are minimum skills you need and it's not math.
So you are not performing any calculations here in terms of mathematical or metric calculation it's
about applying your cognitive skills applying your personality to understand the nature of the project.
Use your existing organization and process assets like templates if you don't have.
You can use the one which is supplied with this school so you can google it you will find many templates
which you can then added and use it accordingly.
And the output of this activity as expected would be a project charter document and assumption Lapsley
have already seen in that document that we have a section for assumption not assumptions are very important
assumptions are basically you can see the up side effect of a project are things which are beyond the
control of her project.
Let's see if I put a fridge in your house.
Now your primary objective is to keep your vegetables and fruits fresh.
Unless until you put them in your fridge or in your refrigerator.
It's not over.
So just because having something won't.
There are certain activities which are required to be done by the user.
And these are your assumptions in terms of a slightly different but more relevant example let's say
you are integrating a system you have a website and now you want this website to send data to some third
party software where it can perform some kind of you know data processing and generate reports.
Now this is this will be a technical implementation where you will be sending data from the database
to that system through some sort of Iscar.
Now I don't want to make it very technical but it's a very I know conventional Zeigler's in that you
know you're sending data to to some other system.
So in this case let's say you are using.
No usually for these days Sonic's simmers.
These are used for data transmission for communication between these two systems.
Now let's say the website is ABC and you are sending data to X Y Z.
Now you project you as a project manager are responsible for changes for this website not assumption
here would be that the team working on that third party system is going to make necessary changes so
that they can consume the data coming from your website.
So this is an assumption and it has to be mentioned here because remember I mean if you have experienced
professionals you already know that these things happen a lot that there are multiple teams who work
on such and such projects and there are conflicts and everybody will start blaming each other.
There are gaps which are identified at a later stage and everybody starts to blame each other.
So it's very important to mention these things as assumptions or constraints orders in your document.
It should be part of your project charter document project management document business analysis documents.
You have to have these assumptions in place.
These are the usage of project chart.
So as I said project charters are being prepared at the early stage of the project and the initial stages
it not only provide justification for the project management but it also provides information as input
for many and their documents.
And these are those examples.
And as you can see it's almost everything about the project because as it will have the business case
and the initial data initial summary of the about the project it has to be deferred for these things.
So it is very important to pay attention while creating your project charter document because it is
going to be a very critical input for many of the upcoming activities and that's it for now and the
next day we will look at that.
Another important activity which is done to create the project management plan.
So thank you.